Renz Aerol Ravela

A goal-oriented developer with a passion for the development of technology that helps the community ease their lives. Knowledgeable in user interface and backend development. A hard worker and quick learner, I have experience in project development and various collaborations and am always excited to learn more.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Freelance

September 2023 - July 2024

- Engineered dynamic, responsive websites using PHP Laravel, delivering robust and scalable web applications that align with modern web standards and client needs.
- Collaborated closely with clients to gather requirements, define project scopes, and provide consistent updates throughout the development life-cycle, ensuring seamless alignment with their expectations.
- Excelled in front-end development by leveraging HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to craft visually appealing, user-friendly interfaces that enhance user experience and engagement.
- Promoted and implemented web development best practices in collaboration with other developers, driving the delivery of high-quality, maintainable code.

Intern Web Developer

Philippine Rice Research Institute

February 2024 - May 2024

- Maintained and enhanced multiple web-based management systems, ensuring optimal performance, reliability, and security across all platforms.
- Implemented automation processes to streamline workflows, reduce manual effort, and increase system efficiency.
- Conducted thorough quality checks and system testing to identify and resolve issues, ensuring seamless functionality and a high standard of user experience.

EDUCATION

Central Luzon State University

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Major in Systems Development - Cum Laude (GWA 1.55)

August 2020 - July 2024

PREVIOUS PROJECTS

Web Based School Guidance Reporting and Requesting System using Laravel $\,-\,$

Full-Stack Developer May 2024 - July 2024

Web Based Document Scanner with Cloud-based Repository - Backend

Developer

March 2024 - May 2024

Web Based Movie Review and Rating System using Laravel — Backend Developer October 2023 - December 2023

FACT - Fish Automated Counting Tool (Arduino) — Backend Developer September 2023 - January 2024



CONTACTS & LINKS

P. Silvino Street, Sto. Cristo Sur, Gapan
City, Nueva Ecija. 3105
(+63) 927-413-7512
renzaerol.ravela@gmail.com
in/renz-aerol-ravela
renzravela.github.io/portfolio

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web and Application Development Proficient in various technology tools
including HTML, CSS, SEO, JavaScript
(React, Vue, jQuery, Express.js, Node.js),
API Integrations, PHP, Python, Java,
Git/GitHub, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL),
NoSQL (Firebase, MongoDB), Wordpress
and Arduino.

Communication Skills - Skilled in project collaboration and team involvement.

Creative Thinking - Skilled in UI/UX designing using Figma.

Problem Solving - I have experience solving real-life problems using different technologies.

TECH STACKS & FRAMEWORKS

JAM Stack, MERN Stack, React, Vue, Laravel, Codelgniter, Bootstrap, Tailwind

SEMINARS & CERTIFICATIONS

Full-Stack Web Development
Certification - freecodecamp.org
Computer System Servicing NC II TESDA

AWS Cloud Certifications - AWS

LANGUAGES

Filipino
Native
English
Highly Proficient